A Finding Aid to the Polly Thayer (Starr) papers, 1846-2008, bulk 1921-2008, in the Archives of American Art AAA.thaypoll
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1929-2008; Series 3; 1.3 Linear feet Box 3-5
  - Friends and Colleagues, 1929-2008; 3.1
    - James, William, 1935-1938 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Koval, Dorothy, 1997-2008 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Kronenberger, Louis, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - K Miscellaneous, 1940 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Lawrence, Martina, circa 1936 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - L Miscellaneous, 1942-1989 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Mason, Elizabeth A., circa 1957 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - May, Benjamin M., Jr., 1975 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - M-O Miscellaneous, 1950-1999 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Parrish, Anne, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - P Miscellaneous, 1940-1991 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Rodgers, Mrs. John A., 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - R Miscellaneous, 1937-2003 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Sachs, Paul J., 1937 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - St. John, Barbara Cummings, 1978-circa 2000 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Swanton, Wendy L., 1990-2006 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - S Miscellaneous, circa 1932-1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Thornton, Nonnie, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Towl, Bruce, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Tudor, Tasha, 1981-1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Wesselhoeft, Fanny and Frances, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Winslow, Margaret L., 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Wood, H. G., 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - W-Z Miscellaneous, 1940-1958 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondents without Surnames, 1944-1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Galleries, Museums, and Venues, 1940-2006; 3.2
    This subseries is organized alphabetically by the title of the organization, then chronologically with each folder.
    Arranged here is Thayer's correspondence with museums, galleries, and arts venues which represented or exhibitedher artwork. Also found is correspondence with organizations that Thayer supported through her patronage. Multiple files are found for The Boston Athenaeum, Boston Museum of Fine Arts, Copley Society of Boston, Harvard Law School, and Vose Galleries.
    - Alfred J. Walker Fine Arts, 2000-2005 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Art Complex Museum, 1995-2002 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Boston Athenaeum, 1977-2002 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1950-2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Boston Public Library, 1988-1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Brigham Young University, 1974-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Brown University Library, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Century Association, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Channel 2 Auction, 1975-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Childs Gallery, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Contemporary Arts Center, 1940-1945 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Copley Society of Boston, 1957-1997 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Copley Society of Boston, 1999-2006 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - DeCordova Museum, 1997-2002 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Doll & Richards, Inc., 1958-1963 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Fogg Art Museum, 1993-1998 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Guild of Boston Artists, 1973-2006 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Harvard Law School, 1985-1998 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Harvard Law School, 1999-2004 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Harvard-Yenching Institute, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Institute of Contemporary Art, Boston, 1942-1980 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Massachusetts College of Art, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Mystic Seaport Museum, 1990-1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - New Britain Museum of American Art, 2000-2006 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - New England Historic Genealogical Society, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Nichols House Museum, 1970-1987 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Nichols House Museum, 2000-2005 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Newport Art Museum, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Peabody Essex Museum, 1993-2006 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Peabody Museum, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Schlesinger Library, 1999-2001 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Skinner Auctioneers, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Vose Galleries, 1947-2005 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Venues, 1996-2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Interviews, 1995-2004; Series 4; 0.2 Linear feet Box 5
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  There are four transcripts of interviews with Polly Thayer and two unstranscribed interviews recorded on one sound disc and one VHS videocassette. There is also one sound recording on cassette of Doris Abramson talking about Catherine Sargent Huntington.
  - "Doris Abramson on Catherine Sargent Huntington", circa 1995; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Transcripts of Polly Thayer Interviews Conducted by Robert F. Brown, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Transcript of Polly Thayer Interview about Nichols House Museum, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Transcript of Polly Thayer Interview for Brookhaven Newsletter The Voice, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Channel 5 Boston Chronicle Interview with Polly Thayer, 2003; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jackson Braider "Radio Stories", 2004; 1 Sound discs (CD) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    This recording contains 5 "Radio Stories" by Jackson Braider, two of which are about Polly Thayer.
  - Transcript of "Radio Stories: Polly Thayer and a Student Drawing", 2004 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Writings, 1922-2006; Series 5; 1.7 Linear feet Box 5-6
  Writings by and about Thayer include typescript and handwritten drafts of articles, essays, and speeches, and notes and notebooks.
  This series is arranged as 3 subseries.
  5.1: Drafts, circa 1934-2006
  5.2: Notes, 1932-circa 2004
  5.3: Notebooks, 1922-1997
  - Drafts, circa 1934-2006; 5.1
    This series is comprised of Polly Thayer's drafts of papers, articles, letters to the editor, and speeches. Although the bulk of material consists of typescript drafts, folders often contain multiple drafts of writing, some of which are handwritten. Polly Thayer wrote on a range of topics such as art, religion, and politics, as well as several memorial tributes to friends. There is a draft of Looking At Animals, an anthology of poems by various writers for which Thayer selected the contents and wrote the introduction. Also included are writings by friends and relatives which are about Thayer or reference her.
    This subseries is arranged chronologically. Writings by others are grouped together at the end.
    - "What the Modern Artist is Trying to Do", circa 1934 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Letter to the Editor of The Boston Herald on Vincent van Gogh, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "Is Neutrality a Thing of the Past?", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Who Are the Outstanding Contemporary Artists?", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "What is Toleration?", circa 1941 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Why Do We Read So Little Poetry?", circa 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "On Marijuana", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Letter to the Board on Establishing Guidelines for Nichols House Museum Committees, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Nichols House Museum May Meeting, circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Westover School 50th Reunion Speech, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "What is Killing the Theaters?", circa 1973 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Preservation Versus Restoration", 1973 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "George Taloumis and the Garden at 55th Mt. Vernon Street", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "On Love", 1979-1991 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Why I Paint", circa 1980-circa 1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "On Seeing", 1981-2004 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Painting Rose", circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Letter to the Editor of The Boston Globe on Thomas Boylston Adams, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Rose Standish Nichols: A Tribute to a Friend", 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Memorial Tribute to Hester Pickman, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "Looking at Animals", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Looking at Animals", 1990-2004 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "What God Means to Me", circa 1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - "What Being a Quaker Means to Me", circa 1993 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Memorial Tribute for Sally Sedgwick, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - "Painting Cornelia Lombard", circa 1995 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Memorial Tribute to Harold Newcombe, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Writing on Polly Thayer's Cat Benny, circa 1997 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Memorial Tribute for David McClelland, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - "Leftover Recollections", 2000 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - "Moving", 2005 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - "Childhood Recollections of Weir River Farm", 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - "Spring in the Public Garden", 2006 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Untitled Short Story by Christina Marquand, circa 1940-circa 1990 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Poems by Friends, 1967-2002 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Memorandum about Polly Thayer's Name Changes, circa 1970-circa 1980 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Dinah Starr's Memorial Tribute to Polly Thayer, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Notes, 1932-circa 2004; 5.2
    This series is arranged chronologically.
    This subseries contains mostly handwritten notes by Thayer that were originally scattered throughout the collection. The subjects of the notes are varied and reference painting techniques and studio ideas, daily tasks and activities, lists, errands, gallery contacts, and general musings.
    - "Studio Ideas", circa 1932 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Journal Entries, 1932-1995 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Guest Lists for Events at Martha's Vineyard, 1936-1974 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Lists of Silverware, China, Linens, and Other Household Goods, 1940-1967 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Art Techniques and Materials, 1941-1994 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Lists of Galleries Contacted by Polly Thayer, circa 1950-1971 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Humorous Verses about Friends and Family, 1961-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Assorted Addresses and Phone Numbers, circa 1990-circa 2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - History of Grace Horne Gallery, circa 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1980-2003 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks, 1922-1997; 5.3
    Notebooks includes annotated appointment calendars, art class notes, and errand books which inventory possessions and list repairs at several of Thayer's properties. The titles in quotation marks are taken directly from the cover of the notebooks and the rest are general headings based on the subject of the notes. The notebooks often have loose papers or clippings tucked between the pages.
    The notebooks are arranged chronologically.
    - Disbound Annotated Appointment Calendars, 1922-1924 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Disbound Annotated Appointment Calendars, 1925-1927 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Disbound Notebook of Art Lecture Notes from New York Trips, 1930-1933 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Lecture Notes from Class on Nature and Art, circa 1930-circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Disbound Binder "Painting Notes: Painter's Workshop Lecture", 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Religion, circa 1940 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "The Technique of Modern Art", circa 1940 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Carl Nelson's Class at Boston WMCA, circa 1948-1960 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Hingham Household" Contents and Repairs, 1965-1981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "West Chop: Dinner Lists" and Repairs, 1965-1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Disbound "Daily 1968 Log", 1968-1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Dismantled Notebook on Errands, Repairs, Guest Lists, 1974-1994 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "Health, Eyes, Paintings, Etc.", 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - 198 Beacon Street Maintenance and Repairs, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - 198 Beacon Street Maintenance and Repairs, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "The Schooner Pilgrim Logbook for 1996" (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - "Old Letters: May Sarton, Howes, Etc.", circa 1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - "Brookhaven: Chores, Telephone Calls", 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Moving Out of 198 Beacon Street, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Atlanta Exhibition - 198 Beacon Street - Wendy", 1997 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Subject Files, circa 1900-2008; Series 6; 3.3 Linear feet Box 7-10
  This arrangement of the files in this series reflects historian Dorothy Koval's arrangement of Thayer's papers prior to their arrival at the archives, particularly the files on people. During processing, several unmerged, but related types of file titles and materials were integrated here.
  6.1: People, circa 1900-2008
  6.2: Interests, 1919-2008
  Subject Files are separated into "People" files and "Interests" files. "People" files contain materials such as articles, obituaries, short biographical profiles, and some audiovisual recordings related to Thayer's friends and colleagues. The “Interests” files include articles and clippings on assorted topics such as animals, humor, and pacifism.
  - People, circa 1900-2008; 6.1
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically.
    This subseries contains material about Thayer's friends, colleagues, fellow artists, and portrait subjects. Materials in this subseries include short biographies, articles, and obituaries. Some of the folders were created by curator Dorothy Koval as part of her and include partial transcripts of interviews with Thayer discussing a particular artist or individual. The most voluminous files are on Francis DeLancey Cunningham, the Howe family, Rose Nichols, May Sarton, John Brooks Wheelwright, and Agnes Yarnall. The materials on Cunningham, Sarton, and Wheelwright are particularly extensive and include multiple folders with biographical materials, correspondence, writings, and printed materials. The subseries contains 2 videocassettes and 1 sound cassette.
    - Abbe, Dorothy, 1991-2008 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Thomas Boylston and Ramelle, 1984-2007 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Alfred, William, circa 1996-2008 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Ames, John W., Jr., 1963-1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Anderson, Judith, circa 1936 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Ash, Tom, 2004-2008 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bancroft, Mary, 1991-1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Bandler, Bernard, circa 1930-1999 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Barzun, Jacques, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Baynes, Ernest Harold, circa 1900-1920 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Beckmann, Max, 1995-2008 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Berlin, Isaiah, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Bundy, Harvey Hollister, Sr., circa 1936-circa 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Cabot, Eliot, circa 1936 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Codman, Russell, circa 1940 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Colt, Charles and Amy, 1982-1996 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cox, Gardner, circa 1954-1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Crombie, Diana, circa 1936 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Cunningham, Francis deLancey (Box 7)
      - Photographs, crica 1935-circa 1990 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Biographical Material, circa 1953-2002 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Francis Cunningham Art Trust, 1996-2004 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Writings on The Nude, 1999-2006 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Writings on Edwin Dickinson, 2000-2002 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Printed Materials, 1964-2006 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Despujols, Jean, 1995-2006 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Fisher, Roger, 1985-1998 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Forbes, Edward, circa 1965-1990 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Fuller, Horace W., 1989-1994 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Galantiere, Lewis, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Gershwin, George, circa 1931 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Goya y Lucientes, Francisco Jose de, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Gregory, Molly, 1987-2007 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Griscom, Joanie, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Hale, Philip, 1968-2004 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Hale, Robert Beverly, circa 1995 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Hammond, Florence and Mason, 1999-2002 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Hawthorne, Charles, 1999-2004 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Herrick, Alice, circa 1921 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Hofmann, Hans, 1995-2008 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Hopkinson, Charles and Family, circa 1955-2007 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Howe Family, 1932-1982 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Howe, Helen, 1955-1995 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Howe, Mark, 1953-1996 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Howe, Molly, circa 1985-1995 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Howe, Quincy, 1964-1986 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Howe, Susan, 1992-2008 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Howe, Tina, 1984-1997 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Howells, Muriel, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Jacovleff, Alexandre, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - James, William, Jr., 1942-1995 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Johnson, Edward and Elsie, 1966-2994 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Johnston, Gilbert L., 1992-1999 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Katz, Leo, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Lampoon, Bob, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Lawrence, James and Martina, 1987-1995 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Leslie, Shane, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Lhote, Andre, circa 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Littlefield, William Horace, circa 1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lodge, John, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Longcope, Duncan, 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Lydis, Mariette, 1931-1936 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Mabon, James Brown and Mary and Candida, 1961-2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 2001-2008 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Marks, Emily, 2000-2006 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Mason, Charles E., 1971-2003 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - McDonald, Marjorie, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - McClelland, David and Mary, 1944-1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Morgan, Maud, 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Morris, Alice Vanderbilt, 1931-2003 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Murchie, Guy, 1990-1997 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Najan, Nala, 1970-2002 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Nelson, Carl, circa 1996-2008 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Newcombe, Harold, 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Nichols, Rose, 1953-1986 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Nichols, Rose, 1995-2001 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Parrish, Anne, circa 1957 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Peirce, Waldo, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Pickman, Hester, 1989-2004 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Porter, Cole, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Preston Family, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Pryor, Luanne, 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Richards, I. A., 1974-1979 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Roberts, Robert, circa 1926 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Rodgers, Robert, circa 1928 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Rodgers, Fanny Colby, circa 1932 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Rousmaniere, John, circa 1990-2003 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Sander, Frank and Emily, 1992-2004 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Sarton, May (Box 8)
      - Biographical Materials, 1984-1999 (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - "Signs of Love: Sarton/Sherman", circa 1997; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 33)
      - Susan Sherman Correspondence, 1995-2004 (Box 8, Folder 34)
        Articles and correspondence from Susan Sherman about May Sarton.
      - Biography of May Sarton by Margot Peters, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 35)
        Reviews, printed materials, and assorted materials on Margot Peters's biography about May Sarton.
      - Hazel Hunley Correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 8, Folder 36)
      - Barbara Martin Correspondence, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Miscellaneous, 1993-1997 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Schroeder, Eric, 1960-1971 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Sears, Richard, circa 2003; circa 1936 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Sedgwick Family, 1954-1996 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Steere, Douglas and Dorothy, 1991-2003 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Stevens, Neyan, 1939-1953 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - St. John, Barbara Cummings, 1995-2002 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Thompson, Dolores, 1996-2001 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Thompson, Leslie Prince, circa 2001 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Toumanov, Leo, circa 1933-1997 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Trafford, Stella, 1983-2004 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Van Ness, Beatrice, 1995-2008 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Vose Family, 2002-2004 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "Vose Art Galleries:Tales of an Art Dealer", circa 1991; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Wheelwright, John Brooks (Box 9)
      - Rock and Shell, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Printed Materials, 1939-1986 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - "Susan Howe Interviews: Thayer, Quincy, Howe on J.B. Wheelwright", circa 1981; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Susan Howe's WBAI radio program had one show titled "The Bostonian" about John Brooks Wheelwright and talks to Quincy Howe, Polly Thayer, Malcolm Cowley, and others.
    - Wickey, Harry, circa 2001 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Wood, Anne, circa 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Yarnall, Agnes, 1940-2001 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Obituaries of Friends and Colleagues, 1977-2008 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Artists, 1979-2005 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Advice from Artists, 1978-2004 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Interests, 1919-2008; 6.2
    This subseries contains articles and clippings on a range of topics such as animals, humor, and pacifism. These files were probably used by Polly Thayer for reference on her many interests. Most of the original folder headings were retained.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by topic.
    - Animals, 1976-2005 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Art, 1932-2005 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Art, 1932-2005 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Art, "Sight-Impaired and Aging Artists", 1965-2006 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Art, Museums in Boston, 1982-2006 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Books, 1948-1999 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Cats, 1994-2004 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Clothing, 1939-1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Death, 1958-2004 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Decorating, 1940-1942 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Graphology and Horoscopes, 1919-1995 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Humor, 1955-2003 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Old Age, 1977-2005 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Pacifism, 1964-2004 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Poems, 1939-2006 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Politics, 1939-2005 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Quotations, circa 2000 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Theater and Dance, 1924-2008 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Travel, 1965-1977 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Organization Files, 1931-2008; Series 7; 1 Linear feet Box 10-11
  This series contains materials related to Polly Thayer’s charitable contributions, club memberships and affiliations. Included are donation requests, correspondence, clippings, newsletters, events announcements, membership listings, organization charters and by-laws, and printed materials. There are also 6 sound cassettes and 1 sound disc. The Chilton Club, Nucleus Club, Religious Society of Friends, and Trustees of Reservations are a few of the organizations included in the series.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by the name of the organization.
  - American Association of Homes and Services for the Aging, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Back Bay Public Garden, 1985-2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Century Club of New York, "The Naked and The Nude Symposium", 2004; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Chilton Club, 1986-2005 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Chilton Club: Phoebe Driver", 1993; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Contemporary Club, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cosmopolitan Club, 1959-2005 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Fenway Studios, 1998-2005 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Footlight Club, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - New England Friends Home, 1965-2003 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Nucleus Club, 1931-2006 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Peace Action, 1994-2002 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Pendle Hill, 1983-2002 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Pine Street Inn, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Poets' Theatre, 1984-2003 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Religious Society of Friends, 1955-1994 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Religious Society of Friends, 1995-2005 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Springfield Museum of Fine Arts, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Tavern Club, 1983-2004 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Trustees of Reservations (Box 11)
    - Correspondence and Annual Reports, 1963-1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports and Strategic Plan, 2000-2006 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Weir River Farm - Past, Present, Future", circa 2000; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Weir River Farm Interviews with Vicki Starr, daughter of donor Polly Thayer Starr", 2008; 1 Sound discs (CD); 1 Sound cassettes (Box 11, Folder 4)